Stamo Papadaki Papers, 1922-1990 (bulk 1930-1970): Finding Aid C0845
Manuscripts Division
- Series 9: Rolls (Blueprints, Plans), 1925-1972; 8 boxes
  Consists of rolls of blueprints and documents. Included are diplomas from Ecole Speciale D'Architecture, a bronze medal award from "Republique Française, Ministere du Commerce de l'industrie des Postes et des Télégraphe, Exposition Internationale des Artes Decoratifs & Industriels Modernes, Paris," and several blueprints of projects.
  - Projects, 1945-1972; 7 boxes
    - Drawings: Jay Hambidge, square root rectangles canon, dates not examined; 1 box length: 9" (Box 27)
    - Building plans: (projection room, workshop), SP, dates not examined; 1 box length: 12" (Box 27)
    - Geometry studies, dates not examined; 1 box length: 19" (Box 27)
    - Site plans (very fragile), dates not examined; 1 box length: 19" (Box 27)
    - Building plans, dates not examined; 1 box length: 22" (Box 27)
    - Greek building plans, 1972; 1 box length: 23" (Box 27)
    - Greek house plans, dates not examined; 1 box length: 22" (Box 27)
    - Geometric designs, layouts (4), dates not examined; 1 box length: 21" (Box 27)
    - House plans for Mr. A. Wrieden, N.Y. & misc. plans, 1945; 1 box length: 20" (Box 27)
    - Exhibit plans: IBEC, N.Y., UNESCO & misc, 1950-1953; 1 box length: 22" (Box 27)
    - Roll 1: Bodiansky, [Vladimir]: plans, sketches (circa 22), 1947 March-April; 7 folders (Folder 1, Item 1-5, Folder 2, Item 6-10, Folder 3, Item 11-15, Folder 4, Item 16-20, Folder 5, Item 21-25, Folder 6, Item 26-30, Folder 7, Item 31-35)
    - Roll 2: Wogenscky, André: blueprints, "M.MI", 1946; 1 box length: 29" (Box 29)
    - Roll 3: House plans: SP for M. Fribourg, 1957-1958; 1 box length: 28" (Box 30)
    - Roll 4: Le Corbusier: typography/layouts for "Modulor", dates not examined; 1 box length: 22" (Box 31)
    - Roll 5: [Le Corbusier]?: chaise-longue & other furniture designs, dates not examined; 1 box length: 37" (Box 32)
    - Roll 6: Blueprints: Brazil, tube marked Reinhold Pub. Co., first blueprint labeled "Escritorio Technico Waldemar Tietz...Cobertura da Biblioteca.", dates not examined; 1 box length: 44" (Box 33)
  - Documents, 1925-1929; 1 box
    - Roll 7: Diplomas: "Ecole Speciale D'Architecture" (3), 1928-1929; 1 box length: 25" (Box 34)
    - Roll 7: Award: "Republique Française, Ministere du Commerce de l'industrie des Postes et des Télégraphe, Exposition Internationale des Artes Decoratifs & Industriels Modernes, Paris," bronze medal award certificate, 1925; 1 box length: 25" (Box 34)
- Series 10: Oversize Material, 1925-1972; 4 boxes
  Consists of oversized material, organized by where they would have been in the other series. Included are artwork, photographs, writings, subject files, and rolls.
  Arranged by series from which material was taken.
  - From Series 5: Artworks, dates not examined; 1 box
    - Miscellaneous, dates not examined; 3 folders (Box 23, Folder 1-3)
    - Abstracts, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 23, Folder 4)
    - Abstracts, Designs, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 23, Folder 5)
    - Landscapes, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 23, Folder 6)
    - Nudes, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 23, Folder 7)
    - Head, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 23, Folder 8)
  - From Series 2: Writings, dates not examined; 1 box
    - Subseries 2A: Books, dates not examined; 1 box
      - Le Corbusier: Architect, Painter, Writer, dates not examined; 2 folders (Box 24, Folder 1-2)
    - Subseries 2B: Articles, dates not examined; 1 box
      - "Le Corbusier: Modulor, The Gradations of,", dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - From Series 3: Subject File, 1932-1939; 3 boxes
    - Subseries 3I: Progressive Architecture, dates not examined; 1 box
      - Awards, covers, layouts, dates not examined; 4 folders (Box 24, Folder 4-7)
      - Layouts, designs, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 24, Folder loose)
    - Subseries 3J: Projects (Designs, Plans and Photographs), 1932-1939; 2 boxes
      - Chair design, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 25, Folder 1)
      - Layout: typography, "Ideas, Custom, Techniques...", dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 25, Folder 2)
      - Plans & Elevations, 1932-1939; 1 folder (Box 25, Folder 2)
      - Miscellaneous (houses, commercial, etc.), dates not examined; 2 folders (Box 25, Folder 3-4)
      - Miscellaneous (New York World's Fair, etc.), dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 25, Folder 5)
      - Commercial Building, 1934; 1 folder (Box 25, Folder 6)
      - Pavillion for Biennale of Venice, 1932; 1 folder (Box 25, Folder 7)
      - New York Airport, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 25, Folder 7A)
      - New York World's Fair (boards), 1939; 1 folder (Box 25, Folder 8)
      - Miscellaneous (boards), dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 25, Folder 9)
      - Theater plan, dates not examined; 1 box (Box 26)
      - House, No. 2, 1933; 1 box (Box 26)
      - Office building on Park Ave., dates not examined; 1 box (Box 26)
      - Unidentified, dates not examined; 1 box (Box 26)
- From Series 4: Photographs, dates not examined; 1 box
  - "Ice Flow" by Art Sinsabaugh & John Rivenburgh, dates not examined; 1 box (Box 26)
  - "Shadow Cast" by Len Lye, dates not examined; 1 box (Box 26)
  - Notre Dame de Paris: photostat of facade, dates not examined; 1 box (Box 26)
- From Series 7: Printed Matter, 1956-1957; 1 box
  - Newspapers: Brazil, "Para Todos" and others, 1956-1957; 1 box (Box 26)
- From Series 9: Rolls (Plans, Blueprints, Documents), 1925-1972; 8 boxes
  - Projects, 1945-1972; 7 boxes
    - Drawings: Jay Hambridge, square root rectangles canon, dates not examined; 1 box length: 9" (Box 27)
    - Building plans: (projection room, workshop), SP, dates not examined; 1 box length: 12" (Box 27)
    - Geometry studies, dates not examined; 1 box length: 19" (Box 27)
    - Site plans (very fragile), dates not examined; 1 box length: 19" (Box 27)
    - Building plans, dates not examined; 1 box length: 22" (Box 27)
    - Greek building plans, 1972; 1 box length: 23" (Box 27)
    - Greek house plans, dates not examined; 1 box length: 22" (Box 27)
    - Geometric designs, layouts (4), dates not examined; 1 box length: 21" (Box 27)
    - House plans for Mr. A. Wrieden, N.Y. & misc. plans, 1945; 1 box length: 20" (Box 27)
    - Exhibit plans: IBEC, N.Y., UNESCO & misc, 1950-1953; 1 box length: 22" (Box 27)
    - Roll 1: Bodiansky, [Vladimir]: plans, sketches (circa 22), 1947 March-April; 1 box (Folder 1, Item 1-5, Folder 2, Item 6-10, Folder 3, Item 11-15, Folder 4, Item 16-20, Folder 5, Item 21-25, Folder 6, Item 26-30, Folder 7, Item 31-35)
    - Roll 2: Wogenscky, André: blueprints, "M.MI", 1946; 1 box length: 29" (Box 29)
    - Roll 3: House plans: SP for M. Fribourg, 1957-1958; 1 box length: 28" (Box 30)
    - Roll 4: Le Corbusier: typography/layouts for "Modulor", undated; 1 box length: 22" (Box 31)
    - Roll 5: [Le Corbusier]?: chaise-longue & other furniture designs, undated; 1 box length: 37" (Box 32)
    - Roll 6: Blueprints: Brazil, tube marked Reinhold Pub. Co., first blueprint labeled "Escritorio Technico Waldemar Tietz...Cobertura da Biblioteca.", undated; 1 box length: 44" (Box 33)
  - Documents, 1925-1929; 1 box
    - Diplomas: "Ecole Speciale D'Architecture" (3), 1928-1929; 1 box length: 25" (Box 34)
    - Roll 7: Award: "Republique Française, Ministere du Commerce de l'industrie des Postes et des Télégraphe, Exposition Internationale des Artes Decoratifs & Industriels Modernes, Paris," bronze medal award certificate, 1925; 1 box length: 25" (Box 34)